<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" /><updated>2017-08-19T18:02:59-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Will Rebain | Blog</title><subtitle>A place for my thoughts</subtitle><author><name>Will Rebain</name><email>willrebain@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">Expectation v Reality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/19/expectations-pt-two/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expectation v Reality" /><published>2017-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/19/expectations-pt-two</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/19/expectations-pt-two/">&lt;p&gt;This will be filled at a later date&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Rebain</name><email>willrebain@gmail.com</email></author><category term="random" /><category term="writing" /><category term="expectation" /><category term="reality" /><summary type="html">This will be filled at a later date</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Expectation v Reality</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/13/expectations-pt-one/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Expectation v Reality" /><published>2017-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/13/expectations-pt-one</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2017/08/13/expectations-pt-one/">&lt;p&gt;I think my biggest annoyance is in matching (or rather, &lt;strong&gt;miss&lt;/strong&gt;-matching) my expectations and the reality around me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It's important to have reasonable expectations otherwise reality will always take the upper hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping the above in mind, one must be honest with (&lt;em&gt;and accountable to&lt;/em&gt;) themselves, at least.  It's about this point that you're wondering to yourself,
&lt;em&gt;&quot;Will, can I truly have reasonable expectations if I exclude others in my expectations?&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My response to you would be to have &lt;em&gt;patience&lt;/em&gt;.  This is a fair question to ask although I would encourage you to contemplate this in your introspection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It's important to have reasonable expectations otherwise reality will
always take the upper hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you fail accountability with yourself, how then would you expect to have the ability to begin to include others into this equation?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; discouraging a perceptive nature; actually it's crucial to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I believe that if you cannot establish an honesty with yourself first you will fall prey to a particular fallacy.  First and foremost, you must understand that this is not a widely sought after trait.  This isn't something that is promoted in public schools, your sports teams, or your extra-curricular activities. &lt;strong&gt;This is the first step.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you reach a point of understanding yourself you become aware of your own personal reality.  It's at this point you will begin to exact the association you currently have between expectation and reality.  Your goal is not to lower your expectation but to aim for improving so that your hopes line up with your actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your actions, as a result, will mirror the expectation you've been quietly holding on to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; discouraging a perceptive nature; actually it's crucial to be successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the point you are accurately estimating reality, you will be able to begin to attribute this skill to more than personal action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start small. Family and close friends. I am not suggesting you take a leap-of-faith with a stranger off the street.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the second step.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experience and an acute awareness are the traits that grow this skill.  There will be times that what you've previously experienced may not happen again the same way you expected.  Also, there will be many times when you feel the 'win' of perfectly expecting another's actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Be Continued…&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Will Rebain</name><email>willrebain@gmail.com</email></author><category term="random" /><category term="writing" /><category term="expectation" /><category term="reality" /><summary type="html">I think my biggest annoyance is in matching (or rather, miss-matching) my expectations and the reality around me.</summary></entry></feed>